<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech Blog 💻 on Thuyen&#39;s corner</title>
    <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech Blog 💻 on Thuyen&#39;s corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Journey of Maintaining Device Farms for E2E Testing</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-device-farm-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-device-farm-journey/</guid>
      <description>Continuing from the end-to-end testing series, today we’ll dive into the practical challenges of maintaining a device farm - something that&amp;rsquo;s much easier said than done.&#xA;A device farm refers to the infrastructure - usually a server setup - responsible for managing and orchestrating E2E test executions across physical devices. This could be a mix of iOS and Android phones connected to a server.&#xA;Maintaining such a device farm can be challenging, and require deep technical insight to mitigate stability and performance issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Packages: Packaging as an XCFramework (1)</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/spm-packaging-xcframework-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/spm-packaging-xcframework-1/</guid>
      <description>Background Modularizing code using Swift packages has become more and more common in iOS development. With the introduction of XCFrameworks, Apple has provided a robust mechanism to ship prebuilt products that support multiple platforms and architectures.&#xA;Binary distribution of SDKs and third-party libraries is not new, especially in closed-source projects where protecting intellectual property is crucial. Another major benefit is reduced build times. Many build caching tools rely on this aspect, ie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Async Let Bindings: a Gotcha and a Closer Look</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/async-let-bindings-gotcha-and-closer-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/async-let-bindings-gotcha-and-closer-look/</guid>
      <description>Swift 5.5 introduced a powerful set of concurrency tools to deal with asynchronous tasks, eliminating the complexity of callbacks and queues.&#xA;Besides Task and TaskGroup for managing child tasks, the async let syntax allows you to start concurrent tasks and bind their results to variables, following structured concurrency principles.&#xA;Yet, be cautious when writing async let bindings. Consider these two declarations below.&#xA;async let x = taskX() // returns an Int async let y = taskY() // retunns a String let result = await (x, y) async let (x, y) = (taskX(), taskY()) let result = await (x, y) At first glance, they seem equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Test Discovery Solutions in iOS</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/in-search-of-test-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/in-search-of-test-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Five years ago, I wrote a blog post about extracting test methods before runtime in iOS. This falls under a broader category of test discovery - the process of identifying test cases in a codebase.&#xA;While test discovery is relatively straightforward in scripting languages, it is more challenging in iOS and other statically typed languages. For a Swift package project, this can be done with the swift test list command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift Testing and the Compatibility With xcodebuild</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-testing-and-xcodebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-testing-and-xcodebuild/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Swift Testing is a new test framework introduced by Apple at WWDC 2024. It offers a range of macro-based features, making test writing more expressive. One of the key features driving migration from XCTest to Swift Testing is parameterized testing. While this concept has been widely available in other languages (ex. pytest introduced it in 2011), Swift Testing now enables repeated test execution with different inputs and expected outputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automation at Your Core</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/automation-at-your-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/automation-at-your-core/</guid>
      <description>We often hear that automating repetitive tasks improves productivity. But how do we decide when automation is truly worth the effort?&#xA;1 At OKX, while managing end-to-end testing servers, I frequently needed to SSH into servers to diagnose issues and retrieve relevant logs (to my local) for further investigations. This was tedious but manageable, thanks to my terminal&amp;rsquo;s auto-completion. However, as we expanded to four servers (two in Hong Kong, two in Singapore), keeping track of server IPs, usernames and passwords for the SSH became a hassle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebDriverAgent - The Heart of iOS E2E Testing</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-wda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-wda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-overview&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we explored the overview of E2E testing in mobile development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to dive deeper into how E2E testing with Appium works on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction-to-webdriveragent-wda&#34;&gt;1. Introduction to WebDriverAgent (WDA)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-running-your-first-test-with-appium&#34;&gt;1.1. Running Your First Test With Appium&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a simple code snippet to start your tests. For simplicity, we’ll run tests on simulators.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Mobile E2E Testing</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mobile-e2e-overview/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction End-to-end (E2E) testing is a software testing strategy that verifies the system integration from start to finish, including apps, backend services, and other related components; to ensure everything functions as expected altogether. Compared to unit tests, E2E tests are often fewer in number due to their complexity and maintenance costs. This type of testing is even more uncommon in mobile development where special setups are often required.&#xA;This blog post aims to provide a quick overview of mobile E2E testing and some opinionated architecture suggestions for incorporating E2E testing into your engineering process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Xcode Recognizes Module Imports</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-xcode-recognizes-module-imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-xcode-recognizes-module-imports/</guid>
      <description>In iOS development, a module is a self-contained unit of code offering a specific set of functionalities. Modules help break down complex apps into smaller components. Developers can incorporate a module into different parts of an app using the import keyword. Behind the scenes, the build system performs several tasks to recognize and integrate these imports seamlessly.&#xA;A module can be distributed in various formats such as collections of source files, or a pre-compiled binaries or bundles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pre-commit Environment Issue in SourceTree</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/pre-commit-env-in-sourcetree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/pre-commit-env-in-sourcetree/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I mentioned pre-commit as a powerful tool to lint and format in a project.&#xA;It had worked seamlessly for me until I committed code using SourceTree. Just to clarify, I predominantly use git on terminal. I only use a GUI app such as SourceTree to view the diff, or to stage selective chunks in a file (which is a bit difficult to achieve when using terminal). Therefore, the issue went unnoticed during my usual workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using pre-commit for Linters/Formatters</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/pre-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/pre-commit/</guid>
      <description>During my tenure at Grab, I witnessed the project’s transformation from an iOS exclusive to a multi-language initiative. Initially, the project primarily comprised iOS code. Over time, we developed various scripts (Ruby, Python, Bash, etc.) to enhance project build time and facilitate CI/CD integration. However, the linter setup was not sufficient for such a multi-language project.&#xA;At a glance, we used SwiftLint, Rubocop, and Flake8 to lint Swift, Ruby, and Python code, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Swift Packages in CocoaPods-Based Projects</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/spm-with-cocoapods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/spm-with-cocoapods/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Swift Package Manager (SwiftPM, or SPM) is a tool for managing the distribution of Swift code. Initially launched in 2015, it primarily catered to server-side or command-like projects. Its adoption has been limited over the years due to lack of support for the mainstream iOS/MacOS development. During this time, CocoaPods has gained its power and emerged as a dominant tool in iOS development.&#xA;Not until recently has SPM been adopted widely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Test Quarantine Logic to Deal With Flaky Tests</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/test-quarantine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/test-quarantine/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Flaky tests, known for producing inconsistent results (success or failure) over time, can be a source of frustration for developers. These non-deterministic tests can arise due to various factors, including code issues or an inconsistent testing environment. In this blog post, we will explore the concept of test quarantine, an approach to mitigate the challenges posed by flaky tests.&#xA;2. The Need for Test Quarantine 2.1. The Challenge of Flaky Tests Flaky tests are particularly prevalent in certain types of testing, such as UI testing, where the higher level of integration introduces greater complexity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Tale of Project Build Time Improvement</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-tale-of-project-build-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-tale-of-project-build-time/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Build time is a key factor to engineers’ productivity. Slow build time can be frustrating and lead to hindered progress. There has been a great amount of effort by the community to tackle this complex problem. This blog post highlights various methodologies employed by our team (at Grab) to alleviate this pain point.&#xA;Background The process of building an iOS project involves multiple steps, including compiling source code, processing resources (headers, assets, storyboards, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Using Python for Scripting in iOS Projects</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/on-using-python-for-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/on-using-python-for-scripting/</guid>
      <description>As an iOS engineer, my recent focus has been on platform work, involving tasks like optimizing build times, integrating CI/CD pipelines, and devising testing solutions. This has led me to explore various scripting options, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found great satisfaction in using Python as our preferred choice.&#xA;The first Python code Initially, scripting wasn&amp;rsquo;t a prominent aspect of my team&amp;rsquo;s workflow, largely due to the simplicity of our CI/CD setup and the prevalence of Bash scripts in our project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Signing on CI</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/code-signing-on-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/code-signing-on-ci/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Code signing in iOS refers to the process of digitally signing an app&amp;rsquo;s executable code to ensure its authenticity and integrity.&#xA;During feature development, developers usually do not have to worry about code signing because Xcode handles the complicated work. Most of the time, we build and run the app on simulators that do not require special code signing settings.&#xA;However, distributing the app requires code signing. While working locally, you can rely on the &amp;ldquo;Automatically manage signing&amp;rdquo; option in the project settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50 Shades of Git: Remotes and Authentication</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/50-shades-of-git-remotes-and-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/50-shades-of-git-remotes-and-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Git is a software development tool that almost all engineers use in their work. This source control tool enables us to make changes to a project code base collaboratively. However, Git can be a headache at times. When running on CI environment, it sometimes does not work the way it does locally. Moreover, we sometimes follow best practices without knowing much about how it works. This gap together with the limited debug capabilities on CI make it even harder to resolve issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cocoapods Explained: Plugins</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/cocoapods-explained-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/cocoapods-explained-plugins/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we talked about Podfile. In this post, we will look into CocoaPods plugins.&#xA;Back in early days, very few maintainers maintain quite some features. It was difficult for them to stick to the main goals of the project given a number of features being requested. Some features definitely benefit a group of users but they don’t quite fit in the picture of a dependency manager.&#xA;Instead of rejecting them, CocoaPods provided the support for plugins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CocoaPods Explained: Podfile</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/cocoapods-explained-podfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/cocoapods-explained-podfile/</guid>
      <description>In iOS development, CocoaPods has become one of the must-know tools. In a team where CocoaPods is adopted, engineers run pod install as often as git checkout. They know how to properly set up a project with CocoaPods, declare dependencies in Podfile, and update dependencies if needed. However, some have little understanding of what happens under the hood. This prevents them from troubleshooting CocoaPods issues if occurred or extending its usage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With Flaky UI Tests in iOS</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/dealing-with-flaky-ui-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/dealing-with-flaky-ui-tests/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction UI testing is a test technique, besides unit testing, to ensure product quality. While unit testing focuses on small portions (or units) of the system, UI testing aims to cover a wider user journey in the app. This testing technique helps engineers gain more confidence when developing, refactoring, and shipping the products to users. In the context of iOS development, UI testing plays a key role in product quality as the form of a feature shipped to users is usually through what they see on the app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI: Heuristically Extracting Test Methods Before Runtime</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/ci-extract-test-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/ci-extract-test-methods/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Reducing pipeline time is a key problem in the pipeline time reduction epic. As mentioned in the previous post, this can be done by dividing tests in the project into smaller sets and run them in parallel CI jobs (sometimes called runners). The assignment of what tests to what jobs usually takes place at the end of the build job, before tests being executed. In order to assign/distribute tests to runners, we must know what tests we have.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI: Thinning iOS Build Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/ci-ios-artifacts-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/ci-ios-artifacts-optimization/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction 1.1. Pipeline Time Improvement As engineers, we always want to land our change on master as quickly as possible. Apart from the time it takes to resolve code review comments from peers, there&amp;rsquo;s one constraint engineers have to face before getting their changes merged. That constraint is the CI pipeline time (ie. the time it takes for a CI pipeline to run against certain changes).&#xA;For iOS development, a typical CI pre-merge pipeline usually involves building the project, then running unit tests and UI tests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Project Labels are not Just to Categorize Things</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/when-project-labels-are-not-just-to-categorize-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/when-project-labels-are-not-just-to-categorize-things/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are a fan of Github, Gitlab, BitBucket, or any git-based repo hosting platform, I am sure you must be farmiliar with project labels.&#xA;Categorizing (Messy) Project Issues A common use case of project labels is to categorize project issues of a repo. For engineering discussion, we use Slack (or any alternative for instant messaging platform) only for quick discussions. Those usually end shortly. If such a discussion become lengthy, probably you used the wrong communication channel 😀?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When iOS CI/CD Config is not Just a File or a Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/when-cicd-config-is-not-just-a-file-or-a-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/when-cicd-config-is-not-just-a-file-or-a-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, when I heard the term &amp;ldquo;CI/CD&amp;rdquo;, I always thought of a dashboard to drag and drop, upload certificates and input the scheme&amp;hellip; blah blah. That&amp;rsquo;s all! And I was kinda believe that a good CI/CD platform must be like that: convenient, as few setups as possible. Now, I have a different viewpoint. What I very much expect in a CI/CD platform is the ability to customize workflow. This does not mean those drag-and-drop platforms are inadequate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tản mạn: chuyện Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/random-thoughts-on-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/random-thoughts-on-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>1 Khi mình join team, công ty mình host các projects trên Github. Một dev mới vào công ty sẽ được add tài khoản Github cá nhân mình vào tài khoản organization của công ty. Lúc ấy, trên Github profile của bạn sẽ hiển thị membership với công ty (bạn phải public cái membership thì người khác mới thấy được nha). Nếu bạn làm cho công ty nào ok, hoặc thuộc dạng top-notch trong nước/khu vực, thì Github profile của bạn sẽ có-vẻ đẹp hơn một tí.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random thoughts on being a CI engineer</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/random-thoughts-on-being-a-ci-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/random-thoughts-on-being-a-ci-engineer/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to talk about my experiences when working with CI/CD for iOS applications and some valuable lessons I learned.&#xA;1 In the past few months, I have been intensively working on CI/CD features in my team. My teammates sometimes refer to me as &amp;ldquo;the CI guy&amp;rdquo;. Before me, &amp;ldquo;the CI guy&amp;rdquo; was someone else who is humble, and quiet. After he left the company, I became the main PIC for CI/CD-related issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: The downsides of lazy var (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-the-downsides-of-lazy-var-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-the-downsides-of-lazy-var-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Continue from the previous post, we will look into a few problems when working with lazy var&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: The downsides of lazy var (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-the-downsides-of-lazy-var-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-the-downsides-of-lazy-var-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Lazy evaluation is a really powerful technique which enhances app performance by avoiding unecessary computation. In Swift, apart from this advantage, it also brings convenience when it comes to coding style&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Config: Run shell script on login</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/config-run-shell-script-on-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/config-run-shell-script-on-login/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I got frustrated with the fact that my SSH keys were cleared from agents after rebooting. As a result, I had to manually add those keys to agents every time my computer restarted (although it&amp;rsquo;s not occasional)&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s best to automate such tasks - I thought. So, I asked &amp;ldquo;how to run a shell script on login?&amp;rdquo;. And here are some solutions</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markov chain: What is a Markov chain?</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/markov-chain-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/markov-chain-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Markov chain is a very important piece of probability and statistics. One application we could name is Markov Decision Process (MDP) used for decision making. Another one is Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC), a popular sampling method in statistics. You may also know Google PageRank algorithm, which is part of the ground of Google indexing technology. The algorithm is implemented on top of this concept&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indicator r.v.s and the fundamental bridge</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/indicator-rvs-and-the-fundamental-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/indicator-rvs-and-the-fundamental-bridge/</guid>
      <description>Expectation (also called expected value or mean) is a very important concept in probability and statistics. One usage we could name is estimation in statistics in which we try to infer the parameters of a statistical model. Another simple application is the step of sanity checks in training a nerual network: verify if the loss function gives a value which is acceptably around its expectation&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MVVM best practice: Inputs - Outputs</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mvvm-best-practice-inputs-outputs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/mvvm-best-practice-inputs-outputs/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to iOS architecture, MVVM is one of the most favorable candidates. Not only does it provide higher testability than MVC but also this architecture is lightweight as compared to its counterparts such as VIPER. Despite that, proper approaches should be adopted to take advantage of MVVM. Otherwise, we could end up with an alike version of MVC with an additional component (ViewModel).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An example of Survey with privacy</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/an-example-of-survey-with-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/an-example-of-survey-with-privacy/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I read the book Probabilistic Programming and Bayesian Methods for Hackers written by Cam Davidson-Pilon and was really impressed by an example of carrying out surveys. Although it is not a standard method with wide scope of use, from the perspective of a software engineer who is not from statistics background, I think its idea is pretty beautiful and worth knowing</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to stub network in iOS</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-to-stub-network-in-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-to-stub-network-in-ios/</guid>
      <description>There are times we wish to fake a network event, for example, a network error. However, integrating a 3rd party stub library just for this purpose is not really worthy. This post aims at demonstrating how to stub network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick thoughts on Tail recursion in Swift</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/quick-thoughts-on-tail-recursion-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/quick-thoughts-on-tail-recursion-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>I always thought that Tail call optimization (TCO), sometimes called tail recursion optimization, is supported in most languages by default. It turns out to be opposite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Method Swizzling: What, Why and How</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/method-swizzling-what-why-and-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/method-swizzling-what-why-and-how/</guid>
      <description>Method swizzling is a very powerful technique that takes advantage of dynamism. The core idea of this technique is to replace the real implementation of a method at runtime. With this power, we could be able to do a lot of cool stuffs. Actually, this special feature is offered by the Objective-C runtime, via message dispatch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Method dispatch in Swift</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/method-dispatch-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/method-dispatch-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Method dispatch is a term referring to mechanisms by which the program determines which operation should be executed (by operation, I mean a set of instructions). There are times we expect a method behavior to be determined only at runtime. This motivation give rise to different mechanisms of dispatching a method, each of which has its own pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How a Swift file is compiled</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-a-swift-file-is-compiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/how-a-swift-file-is-compiled/</guid>
      <description>First of all, this is not &amp;ldquo;how an iOS/MacOS app is built&amp;rdquo;. An app consists of a bunch of source code files, structured in modules/frameworks, each of which could be purely in swift/objective-c, or mixed and match&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Simpson&#39;s paradox?</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/what-is-simpsons-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/what-is-simpsons-paradox/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re from the world of statistics, you may have heard of it. Two doctors, Dr. Hibbert and Dr. Nick, both perform 2 types of surgeries: heart surgery and band-aid removal&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A misuse of Expectation</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-misuse-of-expectation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-misuse-of-expectation/</guid>
      <description>This post is to demonstrate a common use of expectation that is not correct. The example is excerpted from lecture 23 of MIT6_042J</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight initialization - impact on layer distribution</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/weight-initialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/weight-initialization/</guid>
      <description>This post covers some experiments to demonstrate the impact of weight initialization on the distribution of activations on each layer in neural network, especially the very last layers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dive into Histogram of Oriented Gradients (HOG)</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-dive-into-hog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-dive-into-hog/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will dive into Histogram of Oriented Gradients (HOG), a common technique used to extract features of images&amp;hellip; And then implement it in python (in order to comprehend it).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create custom Xcode templates</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/create-custom-xcode-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/create-custom-xcode-templates/</guid>
      <description>Everytime we create a new file, Xcode suggests some built-in templates that may be useful. Luckily, we could also create our own templates.&#xA;Technically, Xcode looks for templates in ~/Library/Developer/Xcode/Templates and /Applications/Xcode.app/Contents/Developer/Library/Xcode/Templates. Let&amp;rsquo;s call the first path P1 and the second path P2. A template could be iferred by a folder MY_TEMPLATE.xctemplate.&#xA;Assume we gonna create a template for MVVM. It should create 3 files: [Feature]Model.swift, [Feature]ViewModel.swift and [Feature]ViewController.swift. Ex: LoginModel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAQ on ReactiveCocoa</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/faq-on-reactivecocoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/faq-on-reactivecocoa/</guid>
      <description>This post highlights some Q&amp;amp;A related to ReactiveCocoa - a FRP framework specifically built for iOS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garbage Collection (GC) algorithms</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/gc-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/gc-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>As an iOS developer, I am quite familiar with Reference Counting. It is considered a fundamental knowledge regarding memory manangement that every iOS developers must acknowledge. Today, I figured out a few more algorithms of garbage collection.&#xA;Fig 1. From left to right: Reference Counting, Mark-Sweep, Mark-Compact, Copying. Reference Counting (RC) This is simple &amp;amp; easy to implement. However, it has some major drawbacks one of which is not being able to deal with retain cycles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: ExpressibleByStringLiteral</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-expressiblebystringliteral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-expressiblebystringliteral/</guid>
      <description>It is a protocol in Swift 3 (which was StringLiteralConvertible in Swift 2). The name clearly reflects the meaning that an object of a class can be expressed by a literal string</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log events in ReactiveCocoa</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/log-events-in-reactivecocoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/log-events-in-reactivecocoa/</guid>
      <description>I used to spend a lot of time reading documentations of ReactiveCocoa (Framework overview, design guidlines, basic operators&amp;hellip;) but, unfortunately, missed this one&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A freestyle way to config UIView</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-freestyle-way-to-config-uiview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/a-freestyle-way-to-config-uiview/</guid>
      <description>This article is to introduce a freestyle way to set up views in iOS (by code).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Generic protocol (p.1)</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-generic-protocol-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-generic-protocol-p1/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we would look into how to implement a generic protocol. A few lacks of language support (Swift version prior to 3.0) would be also pointed out for discussion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Concrete types in Protocol</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-concrete-types-in-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-concrete-types-in-protocol/</guid>
      <description>A specific use case that we are unable to use concrete types in protocol, and how to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Currying</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-currying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-currying/</guid>
      <description>This topic has been mentioned as a part of Functional programming. Though it’s kind of fun to use currying, we often see it on the list along with functors, applicative, monads&amp;hellip; In this article, I’ll show you a couple of ways to have fun with currying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Optional — map</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-optional-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-optional-map/</guid>
      <description>A few experiments with optionals in Swift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Box with recursive data structure</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-box-with-recursive-data-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/swift-box-with-recursive-data-structure/</guid>
      <description>A workaround to model recursive data structure with enum</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RAC 3.0 with Login workflow</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/rac3-with-login-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/rac3-with-login-flow/</guid>
      <description>A particular example of RAC 3.0, applied in Login workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optional - Functional</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/optional-functional/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.com/posts/tech/optional-functional/</guid>
      <description>A demonstration of lazy evaluation using a simple trick</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
