<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Thuyen&#39;s corner</title>
    <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Thuyen&#39;s corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick thoughts on Tail recursion in Swift</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/quick-thoughts-on-tail-recursion-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/quick-thoughts-on-tail-recursion-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>I always thought that Tail call optimization (TCO), sometimes called tail recursion optimization, is supported in most languages by default. It turns out to be opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Method dispatch in Swift</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/method-dispatch-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/method-dispatch-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Method dispatch is a term referring to mechanisms by which the program determines which operation should be executed (by operation, I mean a set of instructions). There are times we expect a method behavior to be determined only at runtime. This motivation give rise to different mechanisms of dispatching a method, each of which has its own pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garbage Collection (GC) algorithms</title>
      <link>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/gc-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trinhngocthuyen.github.io/tech/gc-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>As an iOS developer, I am quite familiar with Reference Counting. It is considered a fundamental knowledge regarding memory manangement that every iOS developers must acknowledge. Today, I figured out a few more algorithms of garbage collection.
Fig 1. From left to right: Reference Counting, Mark-Sweep, Mark-Compact, Copying
Reference Counting (RC)  This is simple &amp;amp; easy to implement. However, it has some major drawbacks one of which is not being able to deal with retain cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>